?
[ Thunderclaps ]
[ Thunder , Rain Continue ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
[ Thunder Continues , Gunshot ]
[ Thunder , Rain Continue ]
WHAT IS THIS ? CHRIST , IT GETS WORSE ALL THE TIME .
THIS JOB DOESN 'T GET ANY BETTER .
ALL SHOT IN THEIR BEDS , EXECUTION STYLE .
ONLY THE MOTHER SHOT IN THE HEAD .
WHAT TIME YOU MAKE IT ? GIVE ME A BALLPARK GUESS .
3 : 00 , 3 : 15 ... AND THAT 'S PRETTY CLOSE .
THANKS .
?
[ Woman ] HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN WAITING ?
ABOUT HALF AN HOUR . JUST A COUPLE OF MINUTES .
[ Chuckles ] OVER THERE , THAT 'S A LITTLE GARDENING HUT .
YOU MEAN THAT 'S INCLUDED ? [ Realtor ] SURE .
IT COULD BE A GUEST HOUSE , WITH A LITTLE FIXING UP .
A GUEST HOUSE ? [ Realtor ] SURE .
COME ON . RIGHT UP HERE .
SEE HOW MUCH PROPERTY YOU HAVE ? ISN 'T THAT LOVELY ?
BE CAREFUL . DON 'T TRIP .
YOU 'LL SEE WHAT A BEAUTY THIS IS .
[ Unlocking Door ] THERE 'S NOTHING LIKE IT ON THE MARKET ,
NOT AT THIS PRICE .
COME IN . COME ON IN . THANK YOU .
[ Realtor ] IMPRESSIVE , ISN 'T IT ? MM-HMM .
WOW . I MEAN , THAT 'S WHAT I CALL CHARMING .
COME ON , I 'LL SHOW YOU THE LIVING ROOM . OH , THANK YOU .
THAT 'S A WOOD-BURNING FIREPLACE .
OH . BE NICE ON COLD NIGHTS .
HMM .
THAT 'S THE SUNPORCH . NICE , ISN 'T IT ?
[ Softly ] GEORGE , I DON 'T THINK- - [ Softly ] BE COOL .
[ Realtor ] WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE THE KITCHEN ? [ Woman ] YES , THANK YOU .
THIS IS THE KITCHEN . NICE AND SPACIOUS , ISN 'T IT ? UH-HUH .
REALLY BIG . HAS ALL THE ORIGINAL HARDWARE AND EVERYTHING WORKS .
THIS YOUR FIRST HOUSE ?
UH- - WE JUST GOT MARRIED .
[ Realtor ] SHALL WE LOOK AT THE UPSTAIRS ? [ Wife ] MM-HMM .
I LIKE TO REFER TO THIS AS A FIXER-UPPER THAT CAN BE FUN .
[ Bannister Knob Hits Floor ]
WE CAN START WITH THIS , HUH ? [ Laughs ]
NOW , THIS IS AN EXTRA ROOM .
THIS IS THE BATHROOM CONNECTING WITH THE NEXT BEDROOM .
THIS IS THE SECOND BEDROOM .
THERE 'S A NICE VIEW OF THE RIVER FROM HERE .
IF YOU 'RE PLANNING ON A BIG FAMILY , THERE ARE THREE FULL BEDROOMS PLUS- -
WE ALREADY HAVE A FAMILY : TWO BOYS AND A GIRL .
- GREAT KIDS . - OH ?
[ Softly ] YOU ARE SO BAD . WHAT ?
CUT IT OUT . WHAT ?
[ Thunderclap ]
NEXT IS THE MASTER BEDROOM .
I LOVE IT .
THERE 'S JUST ONE MORE FLOOR .
SEE ANYTHING YOU LIKE ... [ Thunderclap ]
WE CAN INCLUDE IT IN THE PRICE .
REALLY ? SURE .
THIS CAN BE ANOTHER BEDROOM , OR A PLAYROOM , WHICHEVER YOU PREFER .
I THINK WE 'LL WANDER AROUND ON OUR OWN AGAIN , NOW THAT WE GOT THE LAYOUT .
WE CAN MEET YOU DOWNSTAIRS . HOW 'D THAT BE ?
I-I 'LL BE IN THE KITCHEN . TAKE YOUR TIME .
WE WON 'T BE LONG .
[ Footsteps Descending Stairs ] WHAT DO YOU THINK ?
I LOVE IT .
BUT , HONEY , $ 80,000 ?
[ Sighs ] IT MIGHT AS WELL BE $ 800,000 .
HMM ? WELL , NOW LISTEN .
THE HOUSE IS WORTH 120,000 EASY .
MM-HMM .
IF I MOVE MY OFFICE INTO THAT COTTAGE OUT BACK , THAT 'LL SAVE THAT RENT .
THE BOATHOUSE MEANS I WON 'T HAVE TO SHELL OUT FOR MOORING CHARGES , WHICH THEY 'RE RAISING .
YOU DIDN 'T TELL ME THAT .
THERE WAS NOTHING TO BE DONE ABOUT IT .
I JUST WISH THAT ...
ALL THOSE PEOPLE HADN 'T DIED HERE .
[ Shudders ] A GUY KILLS HIS WHOLE FAMILY ?
DOESN 'T THAT BOTHER YOU ?
YEAH , SURE , BUT HOUSES DON 'T HAVE MEMORIES .
[ Sighs ]
I DON 'T KNOW .
WELL , I DO . THE HOUSE WOULDN 'T EVEN BE FOR SALE .
AND IF IT WAS , WE COULDN 'T AFFORD IT ...
IF WE HAD ... TUNA CASSEROLES FOR A YEAR .
YOU 'RE GOING TO BE VERY HAPPY . IT 'S A WONDERFUL HOUSE .
I 'M SURE THEY 'LL ACCEPT YOUR OFFER .
DON 'T WORRY ABOUT A THING . I 'LL HANDLE THE DETAILS .
JUST GO ON AND GET READY TO MOVE .
[ Door Closes ]
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Unrolling Paper ]
[ Children Laughing ]
THEY 'RE NOT GETTING TOO CLOSE TO THE RIVER OUT THERE ?
UH-UH . SOUNDS LIKE A REGULAR DADDY I HEAR OVER THERE .
I MIGHT FEEL LIKE ONE , IF THAT 'S WHAT THEY STARTED CALLING ME INSTEAD OF GEORGE ,
WHICH , I GOT TO ADMIT , IS BETTER THAN ALL THAT " MR. LUTZ " CRAP THEY WERE GIVING ME .
[ Laughing , Cutting Paper ]
? [ Humming ] WHAT DO YOU WANT TO DO WITH THIS ?
OH , UH- - OH , I KNOW , I KNOW .
PUT IT IN THE LIVING ROOM ON THAT WALL THERE BESIDE THE BOOKSHELF .
THE LIGHT WILL COME THROUGH THE WINDOW AND LOOK BEAUTIFUL .
YOU GOT IT .
VOILA !
AW , SHIT . COME ON .
[ Hammering ]
[ Wife ] OH , I 'M TIRED OF THIS DAMN STICKY PAPER !
I WISH I 'D LISTENED TO MY MOTHER AND GOTTEN THE OLD-FASHIONED KIND THAT YOU TACK DOWN .
NOBODY LIKES A QUITTER .
BUT I GOT AN IDEA .
GET A COUPLE OF BEERS AND GO OUTSIDE AND PLAY ?
WHAT ARE THOSE MONSTERS UP TO ? [ Sighs ]
[ Children Laughing , Chattering ]
[ Tapping ]
[ Tapping Continues ]
HELLO ?
ANYBODY HOME ?
GEORGE ?
KATHY ?
ANYBODY HOME ?
HELLO ?
[ Children Giggling ]
[ Giggling Continues ]
[ Children Laughing , Chattering In Distance ]
[ Laughing , Chattering Continue ]
[ Children Chattering ]
[ Buzzing ]
[ Buzzing Continues ]
[ Children Chattering ]
HARRY , GET OVER HERE .
[ Flies Buzzing ]
[ Buzzing Continues ]
GOD 'S PEACE IN THIS HOUSE .
[ Buzzing Continues ] [ Coughs ]
[ Buzzing Continues ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Motor Running ]
[ Buzzing , Loudly ]
[ Buzzing Continues ] [ Coughing ]
[ Continues Coughing ]
[ Buzzing Continues ]
[ Disembodied Voice ] GET OUT .
GET OUT !
[ Coughs ]
[ Retching ]
[ Continues Retching ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Kathy ] AMY ? AMY , HONEY , DINNER 'S READY .
AMY ?
HERE- - NO , I 'VE GOT HER .
YOU AND THE BOYS START . I 'LL TAKE HER UPSTAIRS ...
AND PUT HER TO BED .
[ Boys Running ] SHE WASN 'T OUTSIDE .
WHERE WAS SHE ? BE GETTING IN THERE AND EAT YOUR HOT DOG . WHACK .
[ Line Ringing , Clock Ticking ]
[ Coughs ] [ Line Continues Ringing ]
[ Phone Rings ]
- HELLO . - HELLO- - [ Gags ] HELLO , KATHY ?
[ Static ]
[ Static Continues ] KATHY , CAN YOU HEAR ME ? KATHY ?
FATHER DELANEY . THERE 'S SOMETHING VERY IMPOR- - [ Static Continues ]
HELLO ? HELLO ? [ Line Disconnects ]
[ Coughing ]
? [ Kathy Humming ]
WHO WAS THAT ?
ON THE PHONE ? YEAH .
JUST A BUNCH OF STATIC . A BAD CONNECTION OR SOMETHING .
I THINK MA BELL 'S GONE WACKO AGAIN .
PROBABLY DISCOVER IT WAS A COLLECT CALL FROM JAPAN OR SOMEPLACE ...
WHEN THE NEXT BILL COMES .
DID YOU MAKE SURE AMY 'S GOT HER DOLL WITH HER ?
YEAH , SHE 'S SLEEPING WITH IT .
YOU HUNGRY , HONEY ? [ Grunts ]
YOU DON 'T WANT ONE OF THOSE CHARBROILED HOT DOGS I DID ESPECIALLY FOR YOU ?
NO , I 'M NOT HUNGRY .
DAMN , IT 'S COLD IN HERE .
I FELT COLD A BIT EARLIER , BUT I THINK I 'VE WARMED UP NOW .
IT SAYS 72 . IT FEELS LIKE 32 .
DO YOU KNOW WHAT I THINK IT IS ?
I THINK THERE 'S A DRAFT THAT COMES UP FROM THE BASEMENT THROUGH THAT DOOR DOWN THERE .
THIS HOUSE IS SUPPOSED TO BE WELL-INSULATED .
THEY 'LL NICKEL-AND-DIME YOU TO DEATH .
HUH ?
[ Footsteps Departing ]
[ Groans ]
MATT ?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ? YEAH .
DID YOU HURT YOURSELF ? NO .
THOSE STAIRS ARE TRICKY . COME ON .
I 'LL TAKE YOU UPSTAIRS .
WE 'LL CHECK THIS ALL OUT TOMORROW , HUH ?
[ Grunting ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Gasps ] OH .
I 'M SORRY , BABY . I DIDN 'T MEAN TO SCARE YOU .
I LOOK AT YOU ALL THE TIME .
I CAN 'T GET USED TO YOU .
WHO LOVES YOU ?
- I 'M LUCKY . - COME HERE .
I JUST WANTED TO CLEAN UP FIRST .
[ Sniffs , Kisses ]
I LOVE THE WAY YOU SMELL RIGHT NOW .
[ Softly ] I LOVE YOU .
[ Softly ] I LOVE YOU BACK .
[ Softly ] YOU MAKE ME FEEL LIKE A KID IN THE BACKSEAT OF A CAR .
[ Kathy Chuckling ]
I WANT US TO WORK . I WANT TO BE THE BEST .
I DON 'T WANT YOU TO HAVE ANY REGRETS .
I LOVE YOU , KATHY .
[ Kissing ]
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
[ Hinges Creak ]
I WANT TO GO HOME .
MOMMY , I WANT TO GO HOME .
HONEY , COME ON . WHAT 'S THE TROUBLE ?
COME ON . BACK TO BED .
THIS IS OUR HOME . DON 'T YOU KNOW THAT ?
HERE WE GO .
THERE YOU GO , SWEETIE .
WHAT 'S THE MATTER ? MEAN DREAMS ?
[ Softly ] SLEEP TIGHT .
[ Crickets Chirping ]
[ Chirping Continues ]
IT 'S NOT SO EASY , IS IT ?
WELL , I GUESS PEOPLE HAVE HAD TO DEAL WITH THIS ...
EVER SINCE ADAM AND EVE GOT KICKED OUT OF THE GARDEN .
I 'LL JUST HAVE TO LEARN TO LIVE WITH IT .
HMM ?
[ Softly ] THANK YOU .
[ Rustling ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Banging , Creaking ]
[ Door Creaking ]
YOU 'RE ONE HELL OF A WATCHDOG . [ Whimpers ]
COME ON , BOY .
COME ON .
[ Door Creaking ]
[ Creaking Continues ]
WHAT DO YOU SAY , HARRY ? IT LOOKS OKAY , HUH ?
[ Whistles ]
[ Door Opens , Closes ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Yowling ]
- [ Hisses ] - [ Sighs ]
[ Chopping Wood ]
[ Chopping Continues ]
GEORGE .
[ Chopping Wood ]
[ Chopping Continues ]
[ Grunts ] DON 'T EVER DO THAT . [ Chuckles ]
NOT TO A MAN WITH AN AXE IN HIS HAND .
I JUST THOUGHT MAYBE I COULD GET A LITTLE HELP .
LOOK WHAT YOU MADE ME DO . IMADE YOU DO ?
THERE 'S A WEEK 'S WORTH OF GROCERIES ROLLING DOWN THE WALK .
WAIT A MINUTE TILL I FINISH THIS UP .
GEORGE , " FINISH " ?
YOU HAVE GOT ENOUGH WOOD HERE TO HEAT THE WHOLE SOUTH SHORE !
HMM ?
YOU TAKE THIS .
I 'LL GET THE REST . I LOVE YOU .
BROKE A BULB .
HEY , WHO DRINKS THIS FANCY KIND OF TEA AROUND HERE ?
OH , THAT 'S FOR AUNT HELENA . SHE 'S COMING BY AROUND 2 : 00 .
- GIVE ME A BREAK . - COME ON , GEORGE , BE NICE .
THIS IS A BIG EVENT IN MY FAMILY .
WE 'VE ALWAYS BEEN A BUNCH OF RENTERS . THIS IS THE FIRST TIME ANYONE 'S BOUGHT A HOUSE .
DAMN REGIMENTAL INSPECTION , AND WE 'RE NOT READY .
[ Harry Barking ]
[ Sniffs ]
[ Gasps ] SWEETIE PIE , YOU SCARED ME .
WHAT DO YOU WANT , HMM ? MY FRIEND , JODY , WANTS TO PLAY UPSTAIRS .
MM-HMM ? HUH , JODY ? SEE ?
MM-HMM . WELL , YOU AND JODY GO ON UP AND ENJOY YOURSELF .
DOES YOUR FRIEND , JODY , LIKE SUGAR COOKIES TOO ?
I DON 'T THINK SO .
NO ? [ Chuckles ]
OFF YOU GO .
[ Dialing Phone ]
[ Dialing Continues ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
HELLO , THIS IS KATHY LUTZ . COULD I SPEAK WITH FATHER DELANEY , PLEASE ?
[ Man , Softly ] I 'M SORRY , MRS. LUTZ .
FATHER 'S NOT FEELING VERY WELL TODAY .
HE 'S ASLEEP RIGHT NOW .
THIS IS FATHER BOLEN . MAY I HELP YOU ?
OH , FATHER BOLEN , UM ,
HE WAS SUPPOSED TO COME BY AND BLESS THE HOUSE YESTERDAY ,
BUT IT CAN WAIT TILL HE FEELS BETTER .
- I HOPE HE 'S NOT TOO SICK . - I THINK IT 'S JUST ONE OF THOSE FLU THINGS .
BUT , MRS. LUTZ , FATHER WAS AT YOUR HOUSE YESTERDAY .
WE WERE EXPECTING HIM , BUT HE NEVER SHOWED UP .
WELL , I KNOW HE LEFT TO GO THERE .
HE DIDN 'T COME . WE WAITED ALL DAY .
[ Bolen ] MUST HAVE BEEN SOME KIND OF MIX-UP .
OH , WELL , NO BIG DEAL . JUST TELL HIM HI ...
AND , AND THAT WE HOPE HE 'S FEELING BETTER .
I SURE WILL . THANK YOU FOR CALLING .
[ Hangs Up Receiver ]
I 'LL GO CHECK AMY 'S BATHROOM . [ Boys Gagging ]
BOY , DOES IT STINK !
[ Boys Continue Gagging , Coughing ]
[ Doorbell Buzzing ]
[ Buzzing Continues ] KATHY !
GO DOWNSTAIRS AND LET YOUR AUNT HELENA IN , AND DON 'T TELL HER ABOUT THIS .
DO WE HAVE TO ? SHE 'S ALWAYS PINCHING ! YES , YOU HAVE TO !
GO NOW . GO ON . COME ON .
[ Groans ] AND BE POLITE .
[ Toilet Gurgling ]
WELL , HELLO , MATTHEW ... [ Laughing ]
AND GREGORY AND HARRY .
WHERE 'S YOUR MOTHER , DEAR ? SHE SAID SHE 'LL BE DOWN IN A MINUTE .
[ Laughing ]
[ Chuckling ]
[ Chandelier Shaking ]
[ Shaking Continues ]
[ Groans ] [ Kathy ] AUNT HELENA ?
KATHLEEN . WHAT ?
I 'M SORRY . I MUST HAVE SET IT TOO NEAR THE EDGE .
I HAVE TO GO . I DON 'T UNDERSTAND .
I DON 'T FEEL WELL AT ALL .
LOOK , I BOUGHT YOUR FAVORITE TEA .
I 'LL MAKE YOU A CUP . I HAVE TO GO . I REALLY FEEL TERRIBLE .
IF YOU JUST RESTED A WHILE , YOU 'D FEEL A LOT- - I CAN 'T STAY !
PLEASE , STAY . NO , I CAN 'T STAY . I DON 'T FEEL WELL .
[ Helena Protesting ]
I CAN 'T STAY . FORGIVE ME .
GEORGE , PLEASE MAKE HER- -
[ Starts Engine ]
[ Brakes Screeching ]
[ Ignition Alarm Buzzing ] [ Retching ]
[ Buzzing Continues ] [ Continues Retching ]
[ Buzzing Continues ]
?
BABE .
AREN 'T YOU GONNA COME TO BED ? IN A MINUTE .
THE FIRE WENT OUT .
ARE YOU STILL COLD ?
HOPE YOU 'RE NOT COMING DOWN WITH SOMETHING .
I 'LL BE ALL RIGHT .
I GOT TO STAY HEALTHY FOR YOUR BROTHER 'S WEDDING .
HEY , YOUR HAIR 'S GETTING LONG .
YOU KNOW WHAT ? MAYBE YOU SHOULD SLEEP IN TOMORROW .
I GOT WORK TO DO .
I DON 'T WANT TO BE UP TO MY ASS IN BOXES FOREVER .
I 'M SORRY .
I DON 'T KNOW WHAT THE HELL 'S THE MATTER WITH ME .
SILLY , THIS HAPPENS ALL THE TIME . NOT TO ME IT DOESN 'T .
STOP PUSHING . YOU DON 'T HAVE TO PROVE ANYTHING TO ME .
[ Sighs ]
[ Puts Out Cigarette ]
[ Softly ] TURN OUT THE LIGHT .
TURN OUT THE LIGHT .
I LOVE YOU . I LOVE YOU BACK .
[ Screaming ] SHE WAS SHOT IN THE HEAD !
[ Whimpering ]
NO . [ Whimpering ]
[ Softly ] YOU ALL RIGHT ?
[ Continues Whimpering ]
TELL ME SOMETHING , FATHER .
WHAT ?
WHY COULDN 'T THIS WAIT TILL TOMORROW ?
I DON 'T KNOW . I- -
ALL I KNOW IS I HAVE TO GET BACK TO THAT HOUSE , THAT 'S ALL .
ARE YOU FEELING ALL RIGHT , FATHER ? I 'M FINE , FINE , FINE .
FATHER !
WHAT 'S THE MATTER ? THERE 'S SOMETHING WRONG WITH THE STEERING WHEEL !
- CAN 'T MOVE THE WHEEL ! - [ Horn Honking ]
WHAT 'S WRONG WITH THIS THING ?
[ Horn Blaring ]
[ Harry Barking ]
[ Barking Continues ]
[ Barking Continues ] HARRY , BE QUIET !
BE QUIET ! [ Barking ]
COME ON .
KATHY !
[ Sighs ] WILL YOU CHECK THIS FOR ME , PLEASE ?
IT 'S GOT TO COME TO 1,500 BUCKS FOR THE CATERER .
THE SUCKER WANTS CASH . JIMMY , WILL YOU RELAX ?
YOU 'VE COUNTED IT ABOUT A THOUSAND TIMES .
[ Sighs ]
YOU SURE DO LOOK TERRIFIC .
[ Sighs ] YOU 'RE NOT GONNA START TO CRY ALREADY ?
MM-MM .
IT 'S JUST THAT , YESTERDAY , I WAS RIDING YOU AROUND ON THE BACK OF MY BIKE ...
AND NOW YOU 'RE GETTING MARRIED .
I SURE AM .
I 'M JUST REAL HAPPY FOR YOU , THAT 'S ALL , HONEY .
[ Sighs ] [ Sighs ]
HEY , THERE HE IS .
GEORGE , YOU LOOK TERRIBLE .
SO SHE KEEPS TELLING ME .
[ Kathy ] IT 'S JUST SOME FLU VIRUS . AMY 'S GOT IT TOO .
LISTEN , IF YOU 'RE NOT UP TO IT , I 'D UNDERSTAND .
HEY , I 'M YOUR BEST MAN . COME ON , LET 'S GO .
- OKAY . - MRS. LUTZ , AM I SUPPOSED TO GIVE AMY AN ASPIRIN ?
JUST GIVE HER ONE BEFORE BED , OKAY ?
OKAY . [ Kathy ] YOU GONNA BE OKAY ?
I DON 'T KNOW .
WHAT 'S THE MATTER ? THE MONEY .
- WHAT MONEY ? - THE MONEY FOR THE CATERER . FIFTEEN HUNDRED DOLLARS !
I PUT IT IN THIS POCKET . IT MUST HAVE FALLEN OUT .
IT 'S NOT HERE .
I 'LL LOOK UNDER HERE .
HAVE YOU CHECKED YOUR PANTS ?
CALM DOWN , JIMMY . IT CAN 'T HAVE GOTTEN UP AND WALKED AWAY .
IF YOU HAD IT HERE , IT 'S GOT TO BE HERE .
WHAT AM I GONNA DO ? OH , I CAN 'T BELIEVE IT ! I CAN 'T BELIEVE IT !
[ Horn Honking ]
WILL YOU GET THOSE KIDS OFF THAT HORN ?
JIMMY , GEORGE , WE HAVE TO GO . WE 'RE GETTING VERY LATE .
[ Whispers ] GEORGE- - [ Jimmy ] WHAT AM I GONNA DO ?
IT 'S GOT TO BE HERE SOMEPLACE .
WE 'LL JUST LOOK FOR IT WHEN WE GET HOME . WHAT ABOUT THE CATERER ?
I 'LL TAKE CARE OF HIM .
I 'LL WRITE HIM A CHECK .
OH , SWEETIE- - OKAY ?
I 'LL GET THE KIDS .
IT 'S FREEZING IN HERE .
[ Shivers ] IT 'S TIME FOR BED , AMY . I 'VE GOT TO GIVE YOU AN ASPIRIN .
I DON 'T WANT TO GO TO BED . I WANT TO PLAY WITH JODY .
YOUR MOM SAID I HAD TO PUT YOU TO BED EARLY BECAUSE YOU 'VE BEEN SICK .
NOW , DON 'T SMART OFF TO ME .
I WASN 'T SICK . I JUST DIDN 'T LIKE MEAT LOAF .
LET 'S GET YOU INTO YOUR PAJAMAS .
[ Jiggling Doorknob ]
AMY ? OPEN THE DOOR .
AMY , I 'M IN THE CLOSET . OPEN THE DOOR .
[ Knocking ]
AMY , I MEAN IT !
[ Continues Knocking ]
AMY , COME TO THE DOOR . OPEN IT !
[ Banging On Door ]
AMY , FOR CHRIST 'S SAKE , OPEN THE DOOR !
[ Baby-Sitter Knocking ] AMY !
[ Baby-Sitter Crying ] AMY !
AMY ! OPEN- -
[ Crying ]
AMY , OPEN THE DOOR !
[ Rattling Doorknob ]
AMY ! AMY , OPEN THE DOOR !
[ Banging Door ] AMY ?
FOR CHRIST 'S SAKE , OPEN THE DOOR !
[ Screaming ] AMY !
?
KATHLEEN . AUNT HELENA .
ARE YOU FEELING BETTER ? FINE . JUST FINE .
I WANT TO APOLOGIZE FOR THE OTHER DAY . DON 'T WORRY ABOUT THAT .
I DON 'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED . I HADN 'T GONE A HALF A BLOCK FROM YOUR HOUSE ,
AND I WAS VIOLENTLY ILL .
I THINK THERE 'S A VIRUS OR SOMETHING GOING AROUND . YEAH ?
FATHER DELANEY 'S GOT SOMETHING , AND AMY 'S GOT SOMETHING ...
AND ... I DON 'T KNOW WHAT 'S THE MATTER WITH GEORGE .
OH .
LISTEN , I 'LL TALK TO YOU LATER , OKAY ?
?
[ Water Running ]
I 'M GONNA WRITE YOU A CHECK .
[ Groans ] LOOK , THE DEAL WAS CASH , YOU KNOW ?
CASH . THE CASH IS LOST . YOU GOTTA TAKE A CHECK .
I DON 'T LIKE CHECKS . LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT CHECKS .
CHECKS GET CANCELED . CHECKS BOUNCE .
CHECKS IS NOT CASH . CASH IS CASH .
YOU LISTEN TO ME , PAL .
I DON 'T LIKE LECTURES ,
AND I DON 'T LIKE BEING HASSLED IN THE MEN 'S ROOM .
I 'M GONNA WRITE YOU A CHECK .
EITHER THAT 'S GOOD ENOUGH FOR YOU ...
OR YOU 'RE GONNA EAT YOUR OWN GODDAMN FOOD .
LOOK AT THIS .
I WANT CASH , AND THEY 'RE GIVING ME A CHECK .
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT , HONEY ?
I DON 'T THINK I CAN MAKE IT THROUGH THE RECEPTION .
LET 'S GET THE KIDS AND SPLIT , HUH ?
I 'LL GET THE KIDS . YOU TAKE IT EASY .
? [ Continues ]
?
[ Turns Off Engine ]
[ Grunts ]
MATT , GET OVER HERE .
MATT , RIGHT UPSTAIRS AND RIGHT TO BED . COME ON . WHY ?
UPSTAIRS AND RIGHT TO BED . I 'M NOT EVEN TIRED .
YOU ARE SO TIRED . I AM NOT !
YOU 'RE TIRED BECAUSE I SAID YOU 'RE TIRED . [ Scoffs ]
HEY , CUT THAT OUT .
I 'LL BRING YOU UP SOME MILK AND COOKIES .
[ Crying ] LET ME OUT .
[ Continues Crying ] LET ME OUT .
LET ME OUT . [ Kathy ] AMY ? AMY , ARE YOU OKAY ?
LET ME OUT .
[ Crying ] JACKIE ?
OH , MY GOD ! WHAT HAPPENED ? I-I COULDN 'T GET OUT .
THE DOOR CLOSED , AND IT LOCKED , AND I COULDN 'T GET OUT .
THERE 'S NO LOCK ON THIS DOOR .
IT WOULDN 'T OPEN . TAKE A LOOK .
LOOK . SEE ?
IT WOULDN 'T OPEN !
WHY DIDN 'T YOU OPEN THE DOOR ? WHY DIDN 'T YOU ANSWER ME ? JACKIE ! JACKIE ! JACKIE !
WHY DIDN 'T YOU UNLOCK THE DOOR ? YOU HEARD JACKIE KNOCKING .
- JODY WOULDN 'T LET ME . - [ George ] WHO 'S JODY ?
SHE 'S MY FRIEND , AND SHE COMES TO PLAY WITH ME .
JESUS CHRIST , WHAT THE HELL ARE WE STANDING HERE LISTENING TO ?
AND WEREN 'T YOU TOLD TO GO TO BED ?
GO ON ! GET OUT OF HERE !
[ Crying Softly ]
THESE KIDS OF YOURS NEED SOME GODDAMN DISCIPLINE .
[ Footsteps Departing ]
LET ME SEE .
LET ME GO GET SOMETHING FOR THEM . GEORGE YELLED AT ME .
YOU SHOULD HAVE OPENED THE DOOR !
JODY DOESN 'T LIKE GEORGE .
[ George Yells ] WHERE THE HELL IS IT ?
[ Man ] THERE 'S AN EXPLANATION FOR ALL OF IT .
WE 'RE NOT IN THE HABIT OF BLAMING SATAN FOR EVERY PHENOMENON .
NEITHER AM I , FATHER .
FOR A MARIANIST WHO THOUGHT VATICAN II DIDN 'T GO FAR ENOUGH ,
DON 'T YOU THINK YOU SOUND A LITTLE MEDIEVAL ?
[ Sighs ] MY BEING A MARIANIST HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH IT .
I HAPPENED TO CHECK INTO THE MURDERS .
I CHECKED INTO THE 20-YEAR-OLD BOY WHO KILLED HIS PARENTS AND HIS FOUR BROTHERS AND SISTERS .
WHEN HE WAS AT TRIAL , HE TESTIFIED HE HEARD VOICES IN THE HOUSE !
HE HEARD VOICES IN THE HOUSE AND THE VOICES TOLD HIM TO DO IT !
NOW , I WAS IN THE HOUSE , AND I HEARD THE VOICES TOO !
I ALSO FELT A PRESENCE IN THE HOUSE !
I 'M TELLING YOU , THERE WAS A PRESENCE IN THAT HOUSE !
HALF THE KILLERS IN THIS COUNTRY SAY THE SAME THING .
" THE VOICES . THE VOICES TOLD ME TO DO IT . "
BUT I HEARD THEM , FATHER ! I HEARD VOICES !
THEN EXPLAIN THIS ! EXPLAIN MY HAND , IF YOU CAN DO THAT !
GO ON ! EXPLAIN HOW THE CAR WENT OUT OF CONTROL !
FATHER BOLEN WAS WITH ME . YOU TELL THEM !
WELL , THE WHEEL LOCKED AND THEN THE- -
THE WHEEL LOCKED . HOW ABOUT A MECHANICAL DEFECT ?
I 'D BLAME DETROIT A LOT FASTER THAN THE DEVIL .
SEEMS LIKE EVERY MONTH THERE 'S SOME KIND OF RECALL .
OH ... I SEE .
[ Laughs ] WE 'RE JUST GONNA WALK AWAY FROM IT .
HAS THAT BECOME THE FASHION NOW , TO COVER UP ?
NOTHING TO WALK AWAY FROM .
I THINK IT 'S NONSENSE . THERE 'S NOTHING TO COVER UP .
I THINK IT 'S BUREAUCRATICAL BULLSHIT !
WHAT DO YOU THINK I AM ?
I AM NOT SOME ...
PINK-CHEEKED SEMINARIAN WHO DOESN 'T KNOW THE DIFFERENCE ...
BETWEEN THE SUPERNATURAL AND A BAD CLAM !
I AM A TRAINED PSYCHOTHERAPIST ! I WENT INTO THAT HOUSE !
WHAT I SAW THERE WAS REAL , WHAT I FELT THERE WAS REAL ...
AND WHAT I HEARD THERE WAS REAL !
NOW , GENTLEMEN , I HAVE A FAMILY IN MY PARISH THAT 'S AT GREAT RISK !
THEY ARE FACING REAL DANGER .
WHO THE HELL DO YOU THINK YOU ARE ?
YOU THINK YOUR SECULAR EDUCATION GIVES YOU THE RIGHT TO QUESTION THE CHURCH ?
SIT DOWN !
SIT !
NOW , YOU HAVEN 'T TOLD US ONE THING ...
THAT CAN 'T BE WRITTEN OFF AS SIMPLE HYSTERIA .
EVEN PSYCHOTHERAPISTS LOSE TOUCH WITH REALITY SOMETIMES .
YOUR EDUCATION DOESN 'T GIVE YOU ANY IMMUNITY .
FATHER NUNCIO AND I HAVE SEEN OUR SHARE OF PHENOMENA ,
AND NEVER ONCE DID ANY OF THEM TURN OUT TO BE SATANIST !
LET 'S UNDERSTAND EACH OTHER , FATHER .
TO ME ... THE CHURCH- -
IT 'S MY HOME .
THE CHURCH ...
IS MY STRENGTH .
AND I NEED HER NOW .
AND THAT FAMILY ...
NEEDS HER ...
NOW .
FRANK ... HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN SINCE YOU 'VE SEEN YOUR FAMILY ?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN ?
WE THINK YOU SHOULD TAKE A VACATION .
[ Bolen ] GOOD MORNING , FATHER .
GOOD DAY , FATHER .
YOU COULD DO WITH A HAIRCUT AND SHAVE .
[ Bell Tolling ]
[ Chopping Continues ]
WHAT DO YOU THINK ? VERY UPTOWN .
I THOUGHT YOU GUYS HAD A SMALL BUSINESS . BELIEVE ME , WE DO .
GETTING SMALLER ALL THE TIME .
WHAT 'S THE MATTER ?
I DON 'T WANT TO GO ANY CLOSER .
CAROLYN , WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT ?
IT GIVES ME THE CREEPS .
[ Scoffs ]
[ Scraping ]
HIYA , GEORGE . HOW 'S IT GOING ?
LISTEN , I WOULDN 'T HAVE COME OUT AND BOTHERED YOU , BUT YOUR LINE 'S ALWAYS BUSY .
NOBODY 'S SEEN YOU FOR DAYS .
[ Continues Sharpening Axe ]
YOU HAVEN 'T EVEN BEEN IN TO SIGN THE PAYROLL CHECKS .
I DID US BOTH A FAVOR AND BROUGHT THEM ALONG .
HERE .
- WHAT DAY IS THIS ? - THURSDAY .
THURSDAY ?
THURSDAY .
I PROMISED THE MEN I 'D HAND DELIVER THESE .
SHOULD HAVE BEEN PAID YESTERDAY .
SOME CATERER 'S BEEN SCREAMING YOU WROTE HIM A PERSONAL CHECK THAT BOUNCED .
I SHOULD HAVE COVERED THAT .
AND SOME GUY FROM THE I.R.S. HAS BEEN CALLING .
DON 'T YOU HAVE ANY GOOD NEWS ?
YEAH , I- - I BROUGHT YOU THE SPOTLIGHT FOR YOUR BOAT .
OH .
COME ON . I 'LL PUT IT ON FOR YOU .
COME ON .
[ Amy ] YOU GIRLS THINK I DON 'T KNOW WHAT YOU 'RE UP TO ?
WELL , I DO , AND IF I EVER CATCH YOU AGAIN ,
YOU 'RE GONNA BE IN BIG TROUBLE .
YOU GIRLS HEAR ME ? JANET , ARE YOU LISTENING ?
NOW , DON 'T BE A SMART-ASS .
YOU QUIT THAT . STOP TEASING ME .
HEY , WHAT ARE YOU TWO RASCALS DOING IN MY ROOM , HUH ?
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Continues Screaming , Crying ] [ Kathy ] OH , MY GOD !
[ Continues Crying ]
THE GODDAMN THING FEELS LIKE IT 'S NAILED SHUT !
- [ Straining ] - [ Kathy ] PUSH !
[ Siren Approaching Slowly ]
[ Siren Continues ]
[ Siren Winding Down ]
HOLD IT OUT . DON 'T LET IT DROP .
I 'LL DRIVE , HONEY .
AMAZING . WHAT ?
NOT ONE BROKEN BONE .
[ Thunderclaps , Rumbling ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
GEORGE , ARE YOU AWAKE ?
ISN 'T IT KIND OF STRANGE NONE OF THE BONES WERE BROKEN IN GREG 'S HAND ?
GEORGE , I HAVE TO TALK TO YOU .
[ Thunder Continues Rumbling ]
[ Fly Buzzing ]
[ Buzzing Continues ]
[ Flies Buzzing ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Buzzing Continues ]
[ Thunderclap ]
WHAT WAS THAT ? I DON 'T KNOW . YOU STAY UP HERE .
LIKE HELL .
WAIT .
[ Sighs ] DON 'T SNEAK UP ON ME !
YOU CALL THE POLICE .
I 'M GOING TO GO CHECK ON SOMETHING . COME HERE , SWEETIE .
[ Police Radio Transmissions , Indistinct ]
[ Radio Transmissions Continue ]
[ Closes Car Door ]
HI , SARGE . WHAT BRINGS YOU OUT ?
INSOMNIA .
WHAT DO YOU GOT ? BEATS THE HELL OUT OF ME .
[ Car Door Closes , Engine Starts ]
[ Car Departing ]
WHAT DO YOU GOT ? THIS IS MRS. LUTZ , SERGEANT .
MRS. LUTZ . [ Mumbles ]
AND GEORGE LUTZ .
IS THAT L-U-T-Z-E ?
NO " E. "
THE BASEMENT DOOR IS THE SAME AS THE FRONT .
WHERE 'S THE BASEMENT ?
COME ON , I 'LL SHOW YOU .
[ Harry Whimpering ]
[ Whimpering Continues ] [ George ] HEY , WHO LET YOU IN ?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING THERE , BOY ?
[ Whining ] NO BROKEN WINDOWS .
HOW LONG YOU BEEN LIVING HERE ?
A COUPLE OF WEEKS .
ARE YOU RELATED TO THE FAMILY THAT WAS HERE BEFORE ?
UH-UH . [ Harry Scratching ]
YOU LOOK A LOT LIKE THEM .
[ Whining , Scratching ] THE KID HAD THE SAME- -
HARRY , KNOCK IT OFF !
[ Growling ]
HAVE YOU HAD ANY TROUBLE WITH VANDALS OR TRESPASSERS ?
WHAT 'S THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN ?
[ Clears Throat ]
YOU 'VE GOT A DOOR THAT WAS BROKEN OUTWARD FROM THE INSIDE .
BURGLARS BREAK IN .
YOU 'VE GOT A FRONT DOOR THAT 'S BROKEN OUT .
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING . SOMEBODY BROKE INTO MY HOUSE .
THEY HEARD ME COMING , AND THEY TOOK OFF .
UH-HUH . OKAY . THEN WHO BROKE THE BASEMENT DOOR ?
MAYBE THEY CAME IN THROUGH THE CELLAR ...
AND THEN RAN OUT THE FRONT DOOR .
I CHECKED ALL THE WINDOWS DOWN THERE . NONE BROKEN .
YOU THINK IT WAS FASTER TO BREAK IT DOWN THAN TO OPEN IT ?
THERE 'LL BE A TIGHTER WATCH ON YOUR HOUSE .
YOU CALL US IF ANYTHING HAPPENS , OKAY ?
OKAY . GOOD NIGHT . GOOD NIGHT .
GOOD NIGHT .
[ Car Door Closes , Engine Starts ]
[ Car Departing ]
[ Crying ]
[ Continues Crying ]
[ Sighs ]
WHY IS THIS ALL GOING WRONG ?
WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING .
[ Amy ] JODY SAYS EVERYTHING 'S GONNA GET BETTER .
MM-HMM . WHAT DOES JODY LOOK LIKE ?
I MEAN , UH ... IS JODY ...
BIG OR THIN OR FAT ?
SHE 'S NICE . MM-HMM .
SHE TELLS ME THINGS TOO . YEAH ? LIKE WHAT DOES SHE TELL YOU ?
SHE TELLS ME ABOUT THE LITTLE BOY WHO USED TO LIVE IN MY ROOM .
HE GOT HURT , AND HE DIED .
WHAT ELSE DOES JODY TELL YOU ?
SHE SAYS SHE WANTS ME TO LIVE HERE FOREVER AND EVER ,
SO WE CAN ALL PLAY TOGETHER .
[ Harry Barks ]
[ Starts Engine ]
[ Barking ]
GOOD-BYE , SWEETIES . BE HOME BY 3 : 30 , OKAY ?
BE CAREFUL .
[ Whispering , Indistinct ]
[ Line Ringing ]
[ Continues Ringing ]
OH , ANSWER .
[ Rings ]
[ Continues Ringing ]
[ Continues Ringing ] PLEASE ANSWER .
HELLO .
FATHER , THIS IS KATHY LUTZ , AND I HAVE TO TALK TO YOU .
KATHY ... LISTEN TO WHAT I 'M TELLING YOU .
[ Static ] FATHER ? FATHER ?
[ Static Continues ]
FATHER !
[ Dial Tone ]
[ Drops Receiver ]
[ Gasping ]
O , LORD , HEAR MY PRAYER ...
AND HASTEN TO ANSWER ME .
[ Scratching ]
[ Thumping , Scratching ]
[ Knocking , Scratching ]
HELLO . EVERYBODY WANTED TO COME OVER TO WELCOME YOU TO THE NEIGHBORHOOD .
IT 'S ALL RIGHT , ISN 'T IT ?
[ Phone Rings ]
JUST A MINUTE , PLEASE . [ Ringing Continues ]
HELLO . [ Static ]
HELLO ? [ Line Disconnects ]
[ Revs Engine ]
[ Turns Off Engine ]
[ Men Laughing ]
GEORGE ... THANKS FOR COMING .
I THOUGHT I MIGHT BE STOOD UP .
LOOK , DON 'T GIVE ME ANY CRAP . I DON 'T HAVE TIME .
GEORGE , RELAX , WILL YOU ? I JUST WANT TO BUY YOU A DRINK .
A COUPLE OF BEERS , PLEASE ? [ Bartender ] GOTCHA .
GEORGE ... ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ?
I MEAN , YOU LOOK TERRIBLE .
HERE YOU ARE , PAL .
JESUS , I 'M SORRY .
YOU LOOK JUST LIKE THAT KID .
YOU KNOW , HE WAS SITTING RIGHT IN THAT SEAT WHERE YOU ARE WHEN HE WAS ARRESTED .
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT ?
THE KID LAST YEAR THAT KILLED HIS FAMILY .
THE HOUSE DOWN BY THE RIVER ?
YOU 'RE THE SPITTING IMAGE . SO ?
SO I 'LL BRING YOU ANOTHER BREW . NO OFFENSE , HUH ?
LOOK , I GOTTA GET OUT OF HERE . I 'LL TALK TO YOU LATER .
NO , WE GOTTA TALK NOW . THE BUSINESS IS FALLING APART .
PEOPLE ARE CALLING . BILLS HAVE TO BE PAID .
I KNOW YOU 'RE BUSY UNPACKING , BUT LIFE GOES ON .
DON 'T PUSH ME , JEFF . I 'M WARNING YOU . I DON 'T HAVE THE PATIENCE .
YOU 'RE WARNING ME ? GIVE ME A BREAK . TALK TO ME !
I KNEW THIS WOULD HAPPEN . I TOLD YOU YOU WERE TAKING ON TOO MUCH .
JUST DROP IT , JEFF ! YOU MARRY A DAME WITH THREE KIDS ,
YOU BUY A BIG HOUSE WITH MORTGAGES UP TO YOUR ASS ,
YOU CHANGE YOUR RELIGION AND YOU FORGET ABOUT BUSINESS ,
REALLY GREAT . [ Slaps Jeff ]
OKAY . NOW CAN WE TALK ?
CHRIST , MAN , I 'M SORRY . I DON 'T KNOW WHAT I WAS THINKING .
ALL RIGHT .
[ Amy ] ? JESUS LOVES ME THIS I KNOW ?
? FOR THE BIBLE TELLS ME SO ?
? LITTLE ONES TO HIM BELONG ?
? THEY ARE WEAK BUT HE IS STRONG ?
? YES , JESUS LOVES ME ?
? ? THE BIBLE- - ?
WHO YOU SINGING TO , PRINCESS ?
YOU SCARED JODY .
JODY ?
THERE 'S NO ONE HERE . SEE ?
YOU SCARED HER . SHE WENT OUT THE WINDOW .
SHE WENT OUT THE WINDOW ?
I BETTER CHECK AND MAKE SURE SHE 'S NOT STILL THERE , HUH ?
[ George ] THE HOUSE IS DOING THINGS .
WINDOWS OPEN BY THEMSELVES .
ROOMS FULL OF FLIES AT THE WRONG TIME OF YEAR .
YOU SAW WHAT HAPPENED TO GREG 'S HAND .
IT 'S CRAZY .
AND LAST NIGHT THE FRONT DOOR WAS RIPPED OFF ITS HINGES ...
FROM THE INSIDE .
OF COURSE . IT 'S RIGHT HERE ; ITS HISTORY .
JOHN KETCHUM .
[ Jeff ] SO ?
[ Carolyn ] THEY RAN HIM OUT OF SALEM FOR BEING A WITCH .
HE BUILT HIS HOUSE EXACTLY WHERE YOU 'RE LIVING .
YOU 'RE LIVING ON SOME SORT OF SPECIAL GROUND .
DEVIL WORSHIP .
DEATH .
SACRIFICE .
GEORGE ...
THERE 'S ONE SIMPLE RULE .
ENERGY CANNOT BE CREATED OR DESTROYED .
IT CAN ONLY CHANGE FORMS .
WILL YOU GET A GRIP ON YOURSELF ? YOU SOUND LIKE SOME KIND OF PSYCHO WEIRDO .
JEFFREY , DON 'T BE SUCH A HARD-CORE RATIONALIST .
EVERYTHING IN LIFE CANNOT BE EXPLAINED BY A SLIDE RULE .
THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR YOUR COSMIC VIEWS .
NOW , DO ME A FAVOR : SHUT UP !
CAN I MAKE A RATIONAL SUGGESTION , PLEASE ?
SURE , MAN . ANYTHING .
GO HOME , GET CLEANED UP ,
TAKE KATHY OUT TO DINNER .
CAROLYN AND I WILL BABY-SIT THE KIDS .
YOU 'VE GOT TO GET AWAY FROM IT , GEORGE ,
EVEN IF IT 'S FOR A COUPLE OF HOURS .
WHEN YOU GET BACK , WE 'LL ADD IT ALL UP .
WE 'LL TALK THIS THING THROUGH .
OKAY .
LET 'S GO HOME .
I 'LL GO IN AND TALK TO KATHY .
YOU ALL COME IN IN A COUPLE OF MINUTES . OKAY .
HEY . HEY .
HEY !
HE TOLD US TO WAIT OUT HERE .
JEFF ... I 'VE GOT TO SEE IT FOR MYSELF .
I THOUGHT THAT PLACE GAVE YOU THE CREEPS . WHAT ?
[ Sighs ]
ARE THOSE VIBES EVER STRONG .
IT REALLY PULLS ON YOU .
I 'VE GOT TO SEE THE BASEMENT . THAT 'S WHERE IT 'S COMING FROM .
I 'M VERY SENSITIVE ABOUT THESE THINGS ...
AND I KNOW ABOUT THEM .
COME ON . KNOCK IT OFF , WILL YOU ?
WHAT I SAW WAS NOT A CAT .
IT COULD HAVE CLIMBED UP THE IVY . IT 'S ALL OVER THE SIDE OF THE DAMNED HOUSE .
LOOK , KATHY , I DON 'T HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS YET .
WE 'VE GOT TO GET SOME PERSPECTIVE ON THIS THING .
HUH ?
COME ON , LET 'S TAKE JEFF 'S OFFER . PUT YOURSELF TOGETHER .
LET 'S GET THE HELL AWAY FROM IT FOR A COUPLE HOURS .
WE 'LL GET DRESSED .
I JUST GOTTA CHECK THE FIRE FIRST .
[ Creaks Open ] [ Carolyn Whispering ] DEMONS ARE SMART .
THEY 'RE NOT JUST MONSTERS . THEY- -
THEY THINK , JUST LIKE YOU AND I DO . [ Closes Door ]
JUST IN REVERSE . YOU KNOW ? IT 'S A CLOSED SYSTEM .
NOW YOU 'RE BEGINNING TO GIVE ME THE CREEPS .
THERE WAS A TRIBE OF INDIANS CALLED THE SHINNECOCKS .
THEY USED THIS LAND AS A SORT OF EXPOSURE PEN .
[ Whining , Growling ]
[ Carolyn ] THEY PUT ALL THE CRAZY PEOPLE HERE AND LEFT THEM TO DIE .
[ Continues Whining ] MY GOD .
THAT 'S WHERE IT IS .
- WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT ? - [ Shudders ]
[ Continues Whining ] [ Carolyn Whispering ] THERE ARE PEOPLE BURIED HERE .
[ Harry Continues Whining ] [ Jeff ] EASY . EASY .
EASY , HARRY .
[ Continues Whining ]
? [ " Jesus Loves Me " ]
? [ Continues ]
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING ?
- [ Carolyn Grunting ] - WHAT IS THE MATTER WITH YOU ?
DON 'T YOU UNDERSTAND ? IT HAS TO BE DONE .
- THAT IS WHERE THE ROOM IS ! - WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING TO MY HOUSE ?
GEORGE , I 'M SORRY . I DON 'T KNOW WHAT GOT INTO HER .
[ Carolyn ] I 'M TRYING TO TELL HIM , THAT 'S WHERE IT IS .
SHE 'S RIGHT .
SHE 'S RIGHT . THERE IS SOMETHING HERE .
GIVE ME THAT .
[ Chipping Bricks Continues ]
[ Chipping Continues ]
WHAT 'S GOING ON ?
HAVE YOU ALL GONE MAD ? GEORGE !
THEY ... COME AND GO THROUGH HERE .
[ Gasping ]
[ Gruff Voice ] FIND THE WELL .
[ Carolyn Grunting ]
IT 'S THE PASSAGE ...
TO HELL !
[ Gasping ]
COVER IT !
[ Screaming ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Rings ]
[ Continues Ringing ]
[ Static ]
[ Whispers ] HELLO . [ Line Disconnects ]
[ Growling ]
GEORGE , YOU HEARD THAT VOICE .
YOU KNOW WHOSE VOICE THAT WAS ?
YOU HEARD IT ! I KNOW YOU HEARD IT !
WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING , GEORGE .
WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING NOW .
[ Police Radio Transmissions , Indistinct ]
[ Gasps ]
PEACE TO THIS HOUSE AND ALL WHO ENTER HERE .
[ Kathy ] FORGIVE OUR SINS . PEACE TO THIS HOUSE ...
AND ALL WHO ENTER HERE . AND SAVE US FROM ALL ILLNESS .
GRANT THIS THROUGH JESUS CHRIST , OUR LORD .
[ Softly ] WHAT 'S GOING ON ?
[ Scoffs , Mutters ] WEIRD PEOPLE .
BLESS THIS HOUSE AND ALL WHO ENTER HERE .
BLESS THIS HOUSE- -
WHAT- - WHAT 'S HAPPENING ?
[ Cross Hits Floor ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Crying ]
KATHY ? KATHY ?
- KATHY ? - NO ! DON 'T TOUCH ME !
[ Crying ] LEAVE ME ALONE , PLEASE .
PLEASE ?
[ Groaning , Crying ]
[ Bell Tolling ]
[ Bolen ] FATHER , SINCE I 'VE COME BACK FROM VIETNAM ,
YOU 'VE BEEN A TREMENDOUS INFLUENCE IN MY LIFE .
[ Tolling Continues ] I LOOK UP TO YOU . I RESPECT YOU . I ADMIRE YOU .
AND WHAT IS YOUR POINT ?
WELL , I BELIEVE THAT ... I KNOW ABOUT FEAR .
I 'VE SEEN IT . I ... EXPERIENCED IT .
RICHARD , I WISH YOU 'D MAKE YOUR POINT BECAUSE I 'VE GOT A LOT OF THINGS TO DO .
MY POINT IS , FATHER , THAT I BELIEVE WE CREATE OUR OWN DEMONS IN OUR OWN MINDS .
I 'M SORRY , FATHER .
IN THE NAME OF THE FATHER , THE SON AND THE HOLY SPIRIT .
LET US PRAY .
FATHER ...
BY THE POWER OF YOUR SPIRIT ,
YOU HAVE FILLED THE HEARTS ...
OF YOUR FAITHFUL PEOPLE ...
WITH GIFTS OF LOVE FOR ONE ANOTHER .
HEAR THE PRAYERS THAT WE OFFER FOR OUR RELATIVES AND FRIENDS .
GIVE THEM HEALTH .
GIVE THEM HEALTH OF MIND AND BODY THAT- -
GIVE THEM HEALTH OF MIND AND BODY THAT THEY MAY DO YOUR WILL ...
WITH PERFECT LOVE- -
GIVE THEM HEALTH OF MIND AND BODY ...
THAT THEY MAY DO YOUR WILL WITH PERFECT LOVE !
WE ASK THIS THROUGH OUR LORD , JESUS CHRIST , YOUR SON .
GIVE THEM STRENGTH OF MIND AND BODY !
O LORD , I BEG THEE !
GIVE THEM STRENGTH IN THE NAME OF OUR LORD ,
JESUS CHRIST , YOUR SON !
O LORD !
[ Crying ] OH , JESUS CHRIST !
[ Crying Hysterically ]
RICHARD .
WHAT IS IT , FATHER ?
I CAN 'T SEE .
I 'M BLIND .
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Rumbling Continues ]
[ Rumbling Stops ]
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM US ?
GODDAMN IT , THIS IS MY HOUSE !
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
NO ! NO , NO , NO ! NO !
[ Thunderclap ] [ Gasps ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
[ Sighs ] NO .
OH , NO .
I 'M COMING APART !
OH , MOTHER OF GOD , I 'M COMING APART !
GEORGE ?
GEORGE ? WHAT HAP- -
I WAS JUST DREAMING .
I 'M SORRY IF I WOKE YOU .
HONEY ... ARE YOU OKAY ?
OH , SURE . ARE YOU SURE ?
HUH ?
MY GOD . WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR FOOT ?
LOOK .
NOTHING . I JUST TRIPPED .
IT LOOKS LIKE TEETH MARKS .
WILL YOU STOP NAGGING AT ME ?
IT 'S ALWAYS SO COLD IN HERE .
LET 'S GET OUT OF HERE .
LET 'S JUST PACK UP OUR STUFF AND GO .
WOULD YOU PLEASE LEAVE THAT DAMN FIRE ALONE AND LISTEN TO ME ?
I 'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE . YOU 'RE THE ONE THAT WANTED A HOUSE !
THIS IS IT , SO JUST SHUT UP !
YOU ... BASTARD .
[ Snarls ] [ Screams ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Continues Sobbing ]
[ Players Chattering , Laughing ]
[ Kathy ] EXCUSE ME . SOMEBODY TOLD ME YOU COULD TELL ME WHERE- -
EXCUSE ME ?
SOMEONE TOLD ME THAT YOU- - HELLO .
I 'M SORRY . I 'M KATHY LUTZ .
I 'M LOOKING FOR FATHER DELANEY . OH .
HI , I 'M FATHER BOLEN .
I BELIEVE FATHER HAS GONE ON HIS VACATION .
HE 'S BEEN VERY OVERWORKED AND- -
I MUST SPEAK TO FATHER DELANEY . I SIMPLY MUST .
Y-Y-YOU DON 'T UNDERSTAND . HE 'S MORE THAN A PRIEST TO ME .
HE 'S LIKE A FRIEND OF MINE .
HE 'S HELPED ME THROUGH SOME VERY DIFFICULT TIMES IN MY LIFE ,
AND I HAVE TO TALK TO HIM NOW !
IT 'S OUT OF MY HANDS .
[ Starts Engine ]
[ Bolen ] HELLO , FATHER .
HOW ARE YOU FEELING TODAY ?
I BROUGHT YOU SOME MAIL .
WOULD YOU LIKE ME TO READ IT ?
I NOTICE THERE 'S ONE HERE FROM A FORMER PATIENT .
WOULD YOU LIKE TO HEAR IT ?
IT CERTAINLY IS BEAUTIFUL HERE .
WHY DON 'T I ARRANGE SO WE CAN HAVE OUR LUNCH HERE ?
WOULD YOU LIKE THAT , FATHER ?
EXCUSE ME , FATHER . CAN I HAVE A WORD WITH YOU ?
OF COURSE , SERGEANT . WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU ?
WELL ... I DON 'T REALLY KNOW EXACTLY .
IT MAY BE JUST A WILD GOOSE CHASE , BUT I 'M THE CURIOUS TYPE .
LIKE THE MAN SAYS , IT GOES WITH THE TERRITORY .
SERGEANT , I HAVE A GREAT DEAL OF WORK TO DO .
COULD YOU MAKE YOUR POINT , PLEASE ?
I 'D LIKE TO KNOW WHAT 'S HAPPENING TO FATHER DELANEY .
YOU SEE , HE 'S AN OLD FRIEND , AND I CAN 'T GET THE STORY RIGHT .
THERE 'S NO STORY TO GET RIGHT .
MAYBE I AM JUST CHASING SHADOWS .
EXCUSE ME , PLEASE .
I THINK THIS HAS ALL THE GOOD STUFF ;
I MEAN , THE MAJOR COVERAGE .
IF THERE 'S ANYTHING YOU NEED , I 'LL GO BACK THERE AND GET IT .
NO , I THINK THIS WILL BE FINE . THAT 'S WHAT I THOUGHT .
THIS IS THE NOVEMBER 14 ISSUE . THAT 'S THE DAY AFTER THE MURDERS .
NOW , THAT CRANK OVER THERE ? YOU TURN THAT CRANK- - THAT ONE THERE ?
RIGHT THERE . IT ADVANCES THE FILM . FINE .
EACH FRAME IS A WHOLE PAGE , AND TO GET IT IN FOCUS , YOU JUST TURN THIS KNOB HERE .
OKAY , I 'VE GOT IT . I 'M FINE , I 'M FINE . YOU ALL SET ? GOOD .
[ Kathy Whispers ] MY GOD . GEORGE .
[ Continues Sharpening Axe ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ Oncoming Car Honks ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Rumbling ]
[ Hammering ] [ Rumbling Continues ]
[ Rumbling ] [ Harry Continues Barking ]
[ Thunder Rumbling Loudly ]
[ Thunderclap ]
GEORGE ! GEORGE !
GEORGE !
MATT ! GREG !
MATT !
AMY !
AMY ?
AMY ? AMY !
[ Crying ] [ Chopping ] [ Screams ]
[ Continues Crying ] [ Matt ] STOP !
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
- DON 'T HURT MY BABIES . - KATHY ?
[ Crying ]
I-I SAW YOUR PICTURE IN THE NEWSPAPER .
IT- - [ Sobbing ]
KATHY , I WOULDN 'T HURT YOU .
[ Thunderclaps ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
[ Growling ]
GET GOING ! NOW ! GET GOING !
[ Both Crying ]
- [ Amy Screaming ] - [ Kathy Gasps ] OH !
GO AHEAD ! HOLD ON , HOLD ON !
[ Amy Screaming ] HOLD ON . GO ! RUN !
[ Gasping ]
[ Screaming ]
GEORGE ! OPEN IT ! I GOT IT !
[ Amy Crying Hysterically ] SOMETHING 'S COMING . PLEASE , OPEN IT !
GO , GO , GO !
OH ! MOM !
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Kathy ] COME ON !
THE KEYS- - THEY 'RE GONE . WHERE ARE THE KEYS ?
WHAT ? WAIT A MINUTE . WAIT .
I CAN 'T FIND THEM .
I WANT HARRY .
- PLEASE , GEORGE , DRIVE . - MOM ?
GEORGE ! NO ! NO !
[ Softly ] IT 'S JUST A DOG .
HARRY ! COME ON , BOY !
HARRY !
HARRY , COME ON !
HARRY ?
[ Screams ]
[ Growling ]
[ Harry Barking , Growling ]
[ Snarling , Attacking ]
[ George ] NO , IT 'S ME !
[ Vicious Snarling ]
HARRY , NO ! HARRY !
HARRY . [ Whines ]
PULL , HARRY ! PULL !
HARRY .
[ Cloth Ripping ] [ George ] HARRY ... PULL !
[ Panting ]
GOOD BOY .
[ Harry Whining ]
HARRY ... COME ON , BOY .
NO . [ Rattling Doorknob ]
[ Harry Whining ] [ Grunting , Struggling With Doorknob ]
[ Continues Whining ]
THANK GOD . OH , THANK GOD .
[ Thunderclaps ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
?